<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<accessorInfo fileVersion="1.0" version="1.3" type="HTML">
    <name lang="en">Deutsche Bahn</name>
    <description lang="de">Dieser Service-Provider liefert Ergebnisse für Städte in Deutschland und auch für viele andere Städte in Europa. Für Städte in Deutschland enthalten die Ergebnisse Straßenbahnen, Busse, U-Bahnen, regionalen Zugverkehr und andere Züge, während die Städte in anderen Ländern nur Züge enthalten. Verzögerungen sind auf fünf Minuten gerundet (es gibt derzeit keine Möglichkeit Verzögerungen mit Minuten-Genauigkeit zu erhalten). Eine Verzögerung zwischen null und vier Minuten wird nicht angezeigt, fünf bis neun Minuten Verzögerung werden als fünf Minuten Verzögerung angezeigt und so weiter. </description>
    <description lang="en">This service provider works for cities in Germany and also for many other cities in Europe. Cities in Germany include trams, buses, subways, interurban trains and other trains, while cities in other countries may only include trains. Delays are rounded to five minute steps (there's currently no way to get delays with minute accuracy). A delay between zero and four minutes isn't shown, five to nine minutes delay are shown as five minutes dealy and so on.</description>
    <author>
        <fullname>Friedrich Pülz</fullname> 
	<short>fpuelz</short>
        <email>fpuelz@gmx.de</email>
    </author>
    <url>http://reiseauskunft.bahn.de/bin/query.exe/d</url>
    <shortUrl>www.deutschebahn.com</shortUrl>
    <fallbackCharset>latin1</fallbackCharset>
    <script>de_db.js</script>
    <rawUrls>
        <departures><![CDATA[http://reiseauskunft.bahn.de/bin/bhftafel.exe/dn?rt=1&input={stop}!&boardType={dataType}&date={date:dd.MM.yy}&time={time}&disableEquivs=no&maxJourneys={maxCount}&start=yes&productsFilter=111111111]]></departures>
<!-- OLD JOURNEY URL -->
	<journeys><![CDATA[http://reiseauskunft.bahn.de/bin/query.exe/dn?S={startStop}!&Z={targetStop}!&date={date:dd.MM.yy}&time={time}&REQ0HafasSearchForw={dep=1|arr=0}&maxJourneys={maxDeps}&start=yes&HWAI=JS!ajax=yes!&HWAI=CONNECTION$C0-0!id=C0-0!HwaiDetailStatus=details!;CONNECTION$C0-1!id=C0-1!HwaiDetailStatus=details!;CONNECTION$C0-2!id=C0-2!HwaiDetailStatus=details!;CONNECTION$C0-3!id=C0-3!HwaiDetailStatus=details!;CONNECTION$C0-4!id=C0-4!HwaiDetailStatus=details!;CONNECTION$C1-0!id=C1-0!HwaiDetailStatus=details!;CONNECTION$C1-1!id=C1-1!HwaiDetailStatus=details!;CONNECTION$C1-2!id=C1-2!HwaiDetailStatus=details!;CONNECTION$C1-3!id=C1-3!HwaiDetailStatus=details!;CONNECTION$C1-4!id=C1-4!HwaiDetailStatus=details!;CONNECTION$C2-0!id=C2-0!HwaiDetailStatus=details!;CONNECTION$C2-1!id=C2-1!HwaiDetailStatus=details!;CONNECTION$C2-2!id=C2-2!HwaiDetailStatus=details!;CONNECTION$C2-3!id=C2-3!HwaiDetailStatus=details!;CONNECTION$C2-4!id=C2-4!HwaiDetailStatus=details!;]]></journeys>
<!-- NEW JOURNEY URL -->
<!--         <journeys><![CDATA[http://reiseauskunft.bahn.de/bin/query.exe?cb=Callback&nrCons={maxCount}&encoding=utf-8&S={startStop}!&Z={targetStop}!&journeyProducts=1023&date={date:dd.MM.yy}&time={time}&widget=1&start=1]]></journeys> -->
        <stopSuggestions><![CDATA[http://reiseauskunft.bahn.de/bin/ajax-getstop.exe/dn?REQ0JourneyStopsS0A=1&REQ0JourneyStopsS0G={stop}]]></stopSuggestions>
    </rawUrls>
	
<changelog>
	<entry since="1.3" releasedWith="0.10">Date values are now correct, also if departures for a date other than today are requested.</entry>
	<entry since="1.3" releasedWith="0.10">Now also recognizes inavailable delays for requests of departures that are more than two hours in the future. This allows to less often update data, because data with available delays gets updated more often.</entry>
	<entry since="1.2.3" releasedWith="0.6.4">Fixed, didn't parse arrival timetables.</entry>
	<entry since="1.2.2" releasedWith="0.6.3">Changed the url for stop suggestions, which generates much less traffic, but gives more information (eg. stop weights). So stop suggestions should now work faster.</entry>
	<entry since="1.2.1" releasedWith="0.6.2">Added parsing of cancelled trains to the departure/arrival parser.</entry>
	<entry since="1.2" releasedWith="0.6">Ported to a scripted accessor (all features ported), added route parsing (for both departures/arrivals and journeys, multiple round trips to get data, with much information for journeys).</entry>
	<entry since="1.1.5" releasedWith="0.6">Added route parsing. The route to the destination is shown for departures/arrivals. For journeys all stops of the route from origin to destination are shown, including departures, arrivals, delays, vehicle types, transport lines and platforms.</entry>
	<entry since="1.1.4" releasedWith="0.6">Added journey news parsing.</entry>
	<entry since="1.1.3" releasedWith="0.6">Uses a new feature of the data engine (getting data in multiple round trips) to get more results when searching for journeys. </entry>
	<entry since="1.1.2" releasedWith="0.5.4"><![CDATA[Fixed the raw url to get delays again (by adding "&rt=1" to the raw url, thanks to Boccaccio.]]></entry>
	<entry since="1.1.1" releasedWith="0.5.2">Added vehicle type "ferry" with icon and enabled ferry-data.</entry>
	<entry since="1.1" releasedWith="0.4.8">Added journey parsing. Parses departures/arrivals times and stop names/platforms, used types of vehicles, needed changes and pricing.</entry>
	<entry since="1.0.2" releasedWith="0.4.3">Added initial delay/"journey news" and platform parsing.</entry>
	<entry since="1.0.1" releasedWith="0.4.1">Fixed the rawUrl so that the results include vehicle-Type interurban train.</entry>
	<entry since="1.0" releasedWith="0.3.2">Initial version.</entry>
</changelog>

</accessorInfo>
